animaljam.com 2019-06-07

# Safety & Privacy | Animal Jam Is a Safe Online Game For Kids

Animal Jam Online Privacy Policy  
Last Updated: Mar. 1, 2019 

##### This policy applies to our websites and apps

This Privacy Policy applies to WildWorks Inc.’s (“WildWorks”, “us”, “we”) sites and apps, including, without limitation, animaljam.com, AJ Jump, AJ Academy: Amazing Animals, and Animal Jam - Play Wild! (collectively “Animal Jam”), and describes how we collect, store and use information when you use Animal Jam.

By using Animal Jam, you, and your parent/guardian (for themselves and on your behalf) agree to be bound by the TOS and our Privacy Policy. If you do not understand and agree to the TOS or Privacy Policy, please do not use Animal Jam.

You can review your child's Personal Information by contacting us or using your Parent Account. You may also request that we no longer collect Personal Information from your child or have your child's Personal Information deleted. To do so, [contact us](mailto:privacy@animaljam.com) at the email address below.

### The information we collect

**We collect all of the following types of information (collectively “Information”). Additionally, from here on out, any reference to “children” means individuals under the age of 13.**

**Children's Information.** We collect what is reasonably necessary for children to participate on our site such as usernames, passwords, gender, age, and chat logs. This may include Personal Information and Anonymous Information. 

**Personal Information:** specific identifiable information about an individual or entity which may be used to identify, contact or locate that person or entity (e.g. name, mailing address, device ID, email address, phone number, online user profile name). 

**Anonymous Information (Non-Personal):** information that, by itself, does not identify a specific individual or entity (e.g. demographic information, usage data or downloads)

**Financial Information:** information relating to payments and billing (e.g. name, account information, billing address) provided by you. We do not knowingly collect Financial Information from users under 13, although we may collect it from parents via their Parent Account.

**Parent's Information.** We collect parent's email addresses. We may collect this from the child or the parent. We may also collect credit card numbers from parents who have a paid account on our site. 

**Other information.** If you or your child uses our website, we may collect information about the browser used or user's IP address to identify the country of origin. We might look at what site you or your child came from, or visit next. We may collect passive information about what activity the child did or how long the child played. We only use this information for support of our internal operations and do not share this information with third parties unless there is a reason to support internal operations. 

### How we collect information

**We collect Information directly.** For example, if you or your child create an account with us. We also collect information if you or your child contacts us. 

**We collect Information passively.** From time to time we may use common tracking tools (e.g. Google Analytics) for internal purposes. 

### How we use information

**How we use children's Personal Information.** Unless permitted by law, we only use children's Personal Information after getting parental consent. In some circumstances we may not request parental consent. For example, if we are only going to use the information one time to respond to a direct request. Or if we are using Personal Information obtained from a child to get parental consent. We also use children's information as described in any request for parental consent.

**How we use parent and guardian Personal Information.** We use email addresses to notify parents or guardians that their children have registered on our site. We may also use email addresses to communicate about your child's account. We have a parent-directed newsletter that we send to people who sign up to receive it through their Parent Account.

**We use children and parent's Personal Information and Anonymous Information to improve our products and services.** We may use Information to make our website and products better. We might use Information to customize you or your child's experience with us. For example, we might use Information to store your child's password if he or she registers for our site. We also have different methods of chat (more info found [here](https://help.animaljam.com/hc/en-us/articles/202832200)) that players may utilize, which parents can control through their Parent Account, and we collect and use this information to improve the gameplay experience and promote safety. 

**We use Information for security purposes.** We may use any Information we collect to protect our company, our customers, and our websites.

**We use Information for marketing purposes.** For example, we might use Personal Information to send adults details about new site features. We might use Personal Information send adults third party offers or products we think you might find interesting. 

**We use Information as otherwise disclosed or permitted by law.** For example, we will use Information about children as we describe in parental consent requests.

### Third Parties

**We may share Information.** We will share Information if we're required to by law, or if we have to respond to a court order or subpoena. We may share it if a government agency or investigatory body requests. We might share Information when we are investigating potential fraud. We will also share Personal Information and Anonymous Information with vendors who help us run our site. In some features, we may allow children to share monitored communications and interactions with other players. These features are only available to accounts with verified parental consent. 

**We will share information with third parties who perform services on our behalf.** For example, we share Personal Information and Anonymous Information with vendors who help us send emails and operate our sites. We also share Personal Information and Financial Information with vendors to complete payments.

You can find a list of third-party operators who collect persistent identifiers on our sites and applications here

### Third Party Service Providers

  * Ad2Games
  * *AdColony
  * *Apple Search Ads
  * *AppsFlyer
  * Bing Ads
  * Commission Junction

  * *Facebook
  * Google Analytics
  * **Google Adwords
  * Google Tag Manager
  * Nat Geo Kids
  * New Relic

  * **Secco Squared
  * SuperAwesome
  * *Unity Ads
  * *Vungle
  * **Zendesk

Exclusive to Animal Jam

Exclusive to Animal Jam – Play Wild!

Used jointly between Animal Jam and Animal Jam – Play Wild!

Please contact us below with questions about the privacy policies, collection and use practices of these third parties:

Animal Jam  
PO Box 3624  
Salt Lake City, UT 84110-3624  

**We may share, transfer or assign Information to any successor to all or part of our business.** For example, if part of our business was sold we may give our user Information as part of that transaction.

**We may share Information for other reasons we may describe to you.**

### Email Lists & Cookies

**You can opt out of receiving our marketing emails.** To stop receiving our promotional emails, follow the instructions in any promotional message you get from us. Don't worry! Even if you opt out of getting marketing messages, we will still send you transactional messages. These include responses to your questions, information about your children, or information about your account or your orders.

To opt out, change your communication settings in your Parent Account.

**You can control cookies and tracking tools.** Your browser may give you the ability to control cookies. How you do so depends on the type of cookie. Certain browsers can be set to reject browser cookies. To control flash cookies, which we may use on certain websites from time to time, you can go here. Why? Because flash cookies cannot be controlled through your browser settings. NOTE: If you block cookies on your browser, certain features on our sites may not work.

### California Privacy Rights

Since 2005, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our customers who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. We do not share our customer's personal information with unaffiliated third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. For inquiries regarding our disclosure policy, please send -us an email to support@animaljam.com, or write us at: Animal Jam PO Box 3624, Salt Lake City, UT 84110-3624. We will be happy to honor your request.

### California Privacy Rights for Minor Users

Since January 1, 2015, California Business and Professions Code Section 22581 permits you, if you are a California resident under the age of 18, to view, correct, or remove information provided by you or publicly posted by you, by accessing your Animal Jam account and editing/removing your Information. You will need your password to access your personal account. You may also send us an email asking us to remove certain posted content at support@animaljam.com. In the alternative, you may write to us at Animal Jam PO Box 3624, Salt Lake City, UT 84110-3624.

We will be happy to review, update or remove Information and/or content as appropriate. Residual copies of information and/or content that have been removed from your account may remain in our backup systems for approximately one month. We may still retain your information to resolve disputes, enforce our user agreement, or comply with legal requirements; in this case, your personal information will be blocked from use for any other purpose.

### Security

The Internet is not 100 percent secure. We cannot promise that your use of our sites will be completely safe. We encourage you to use caution when using the Internet. This includes not sharing your passwords. We keep Personal Information as long as it is necessary or relevant for the practices described in this Policy. We also keep information as otherwise required by law.

We filter and moderate our online chat. We also filter usernames in an attempt ensure they don't have children’s Personal Information. Parents, you can take steps to protect your kids too. To learn more about how to protect your child online, read the helpful [information provided by the FTC](http://www.onguardonline.gov/). Please also read [this bulletin](http://www.onguardonline.gov/articles/0031-protecting-your-childs-privacy-online).

### Where we store information

Information we maintain may be stored both within and outside of the United States. If you live outside of the United States, you understand and agree that we may transfer your information to the United States. This site is subject to U.S. laws, which may not afford the same level of protection as those in your country.

### Hyperlinks

If you click on a link to a third party site, you will be taken to websites we do not control. This includes social media sites. This policy does not apply to the privacy practices of these websites. Read the privacy policy of other websites and insurance carriers carefully. We are not responsible for these third party practices.

### Policy Updates

From time to time we may change our privacy policies. We will notify you of any material changes to our Policy as required by law. We will also post an updated copy on our website. Please check our site periodically for updates.

### Caru Safe Harbor

We are a participating member of the CARU Safe Harbor Program. If you believe that we have not responded to your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, please contact CARU at:

CARU Safe Harbor  
Attn: Director  
112 Madison Avenue, 3rd Floor  
New York, NY 10016  
caru@caru.bbb.org
